Josiah Willard Gibbs Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Letter by and to J. Willard Gibbs (1790-1861), 1811-1860; Series V; 0.83
  - Letters to J. Willard Gibbs
    - Budington, William Ives (1815-1879) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Andover, Massachusetts., 1851 August 30 (Box 20, Folder 326)
    - Bulkley, Chauncey - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Philadelphia., 1859 April 15 (Box 20, Folder 327)
    - Bushnell, Horace (1802-1876) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Hartford., 1854 April 4 (Box 20, Folder 328)
    - Byington, Cyrus (1793-1868) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1833 July (Box 20, Folder 329)
      Includes the Lord's Prayer in Choctaw.
    - Carnahan, James (1775-1859) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Princeton., 1853 July 6 (Box 20, Folder 330)
    - Cary, J. Addison - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1844 September 28 (Box 20, Folder 331)
    - Chapin, Joel - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Trumbull., 1850 August 9 and September 2 (Box 20, Folder 332)
    - Chesebrough, Amos I. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Chester, Connecticut., 1851 June 26 (Box 20, Folder 333)
    - Clapp, L. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Wisconsin., 1849 December 6 (Box 20, Folder 334)
    - Cleveland, Charles Dexter (1802-1869) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Philadelphia., 1858 December 10, 1860 September 24 (Box 20, Folder 335)
    - Conant, Thomas Jefferson (1802-1891) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Rochester., 1855 September 14 (Box 20, Folder 336)
    - Converse, A. - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Philadelphia., 1845 May 1 and December 18 (Box 20, Folder 337)
    - Crowell, Edward P. - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Amherst, Massachusetts., 1858 December 31, 1859 February 15 (Box 20, Folder 338)
    - Cushing, T. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Boston., 1846 May 8 (Box 20, Folder 339)
    - Dabney, Jonathan Peele (d. 1868) - 8 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Salem and Boston., 1836-1844 (Box 20, Folder 340)
    - Day, George Edward (1815-1905) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Tubingen, Germany; Northampton; Lane Seminary., 1844 August 5, 1848 October 12, 1852 March 25 (Box 20, Folder 341)
    - Der-Sahazyan, Hohanness B. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Ada-Razar., 1849 September 26 (Box 20, Folder 342)
    - D'Israel, Mr. - Autograph confession of faith to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1843 June (Box 20, Folder 343)
    - Dixwell, Epes Sargent (1807-1899) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Cambridge, Massachusetts., 1858 June 1 (Box 20, Folder 344)
    - Dobie, David - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Plattsburgh, New York., 1852 November 1 (Box 20, Folder 345)
    - Dwight, Benjamin Woodbridge (1816-1889) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Clinton, New York., 1841 September 25, 1860 November 13 (Box 20, Folder 346)
    - Edmands, John - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Philadelphia., 1856 April 23, 1858 December 14 (Box 20, Folder 347)
    - Eichthal and Bernhard - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1843 July 28 (Box 20, Folder 348)
    - Edwards, B. B. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Andover., 1848 November 15 (Box 20, Folder 349)
    - Elton, Romeo (1790-1870) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Exeter, England., 1859 March 31 (Box 20, Folder 350)
    - Eames, Theodore - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Brooklyn., 1839 August 10 (Box 20, Folder 351)
    - Francis, Convers - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Cambridge., 1859 January 1 (Box 20, Folder 352)
    - Fletcher, Mr. - Printed circuler, Massachusetts Herald, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1839 October 12 (Box 20, Folder 353)
    - Fisher, George Park (1827-1909) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Andover, Massachusetts., 1854 August 17 (Box 20, Folder 354)
    - Fowler, William C. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Amherst., 1853 December 26 (Box 20, Folder 355)
    - Foote, Charles - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Middletown., 1831 January 3 (Box 20, Folder 356)
    - Gildemeister, Edward - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1841 May 24 (Box 20, Folder 357)
    - Goldsmith, B. M. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Southport., 1843 September 28 (Box 20, Folder 358)
    - Green, John C. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1840 June 23 (Box 20, Folder 359)
    - Grout, Lewis (1815-1905) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Africa., 1850 July 29, 1853 February 17 and August 29 (Box 20, Folder 360)
    - Hadley, James Jr. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1844 August 30
    - Hackett, Horation Balch (1808-1875) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Newton Center, Massachusetts., 1847 May 25 (Box 20, Folder 361)
    - Hammond, Charles - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Groton., 1858 May 24 (Box 20, Folder 362)
    - Hart, Lucius - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1844 September 28 (Box 20, Folder 363)
    - Henry, Joseph - 3 autograph letters, signed, 1 letter, signed, and 1 copy of a letter to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Washington, D. C., 1849-1852, no date (Box 20, Folder 364)
    - Herrick, E. C. - 1 autograph letter, signed, and 1 autograph note, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1851 July 23 and August 4 (Box 20, Folder 365)
    - Higginson, Stephen (1770-1834) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Cambridge., 1829 February 8 and April 28, 1833 June 11 (Box 20, Folder 366)
    - Hillhouse, Augustus Lucas (1791-1859) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1811 November 8 (Box 20, Folder 367)
    - Hillier, C. M. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Hong Kong., 1846 April 15 (Box 20, Folder 368)
    - Homer, Jona - Reprint from a newspaper with manuscript note to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1830 August 28 (Box 20, Folder 369)
      Includes newspaper clipping.
    - Homes, Henry Augustus (1812-1887) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Boston and Albany., 1841 April 2, 1855 April 23 (Box 20, Folder 370)
    - Hordynsky, Henry de - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1844 October 17, October 30 (Box 20, Folder 371)
    - Hosington, H. W. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Williamstown., 1852 May 1 (Box 20, Folder 372)
    - Hoyt, J. B. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Coventry., 1852 August 19
    - Hunt, Ralph - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1843 July 12 (Box 20, Folder 373)
    - Huntington, Frederic Dan (1819-1904) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Cambridge., 1858 December 13 (Box 20, Folder 374)
    - Hutchinson, Enoch - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Boston., 1841 June 22 (Box 20, Folder 375)
    - Jewett, Stephen - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Derby., 1831 March 21 (Box 21, Folder 376)
    - Johnson, Ebenezer Alfred (1813-1891) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1852 June 11 (Box 21, Folder 377)
    - Kilbourn, Payne K. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Litchfield., 1848 February 11 (Box 21, Folder 378)
      Includes one page of proof.
    - Kent, Aratus - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Galina., 1860 June 20 (Box 21, Folder 379)
    - Larned, William Augustus (1806-1862) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Millbury and Troy., 1835 September 11 and December 14 (Box 21, Folder 380)
    - Laughlin, William - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Canal Onondaga, New York., 1858 April 17 (Box 21, Folder 381)
    - Leavitt, Joshua (1794-1873) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1835 April 25 (Box 21, Folder 382)
    - Lee, Charles M. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Rochester., 1832 April 11 (Box 21, Folder 383)
    - Lee, Johnathan (1786-1866) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Salisbury., 1846 January 19, 1850 August 13, 1853 September 2 (Box 21, Folder 384)
    - Lindsay, J. W. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Middletown., 1858 December 13 (Box 21, Folder 385)
    - Lobdell, Henry (1827-1855) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Auburn, New York; Danbury, Connecticut; Mosul, Turkey., 1850 February 5, 1851 July 3, 1854 January 5 (Box 21, Folder 386)
    - Lockwood, Peter - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Berkshire, New York., 1844 July 27 and August 5 (Box 21, Folder 387)
    - Lord, David Nevins (1792-1880) - 10 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1850-1856 (Box 21, Folder 388)
    - Lowrie, Walter - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1845 June 28 (Box 21, Folder 389)
    - Maclean, John (1800-1886) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Princeton., 1853 August 19 (Box 21, Folder 390)
    - MacWhorter, Alexander - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1857 May 22 (Box 21, Folder 391)
    - Macy, William Allen (1825-1859) - 7 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Various places., 1845-1858 (Box 21, Folder 392)
    - Marsh, George Perkins (1801-1882) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Burlington., 1860 October 23 (Box 21, Folder 393)
    - Martin, Benjamin Nicholas (1816-1883) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Albany., 1852 May 25 (Box 21, Folder 394)
    - Meigs, Benjamin C. (1789-1862) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Jaffna, Ceylon., 1843 October 16 (Box 21, Folder 395)
    - Meigs, L. H. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1852 March 2 (Box 21, Folder 396)
    - Moffat, James Clement (1811-1890) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Princeton., 1859 April 8 (Box 21, Folder 397)
    - Morrison, J. Robert - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Macao, China., 1836 January 1 (Box 21, Folder 398)
    - Morrison, Robert - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Macao, China., 1842 April 9 (Box 21, Folder 399)
    - Murdock, Abraham - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Columbus, Mississippi., 1859 August 13, 1860 January 14 (Box 21, Folder 400)
    - Nazro, John Coffin - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). White's White Mountain House., 1850 August 29 (Box 21, Folder 401)
    - New Haven, Secretary of the Horticultural Society of - Typed letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1821 December 1 (Box 21, Folder 402)
    - Nordheimer, Isaac - Prospectus of a Hebrew Concordance., 1842 January 1 (Box 21, Folder 403)
    - Olyphant, Talbot - 4 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1840 June 2, 1845 September 27 and October 8 and 10 (Box 21, Folder 404)
    - Park, Edwards Amasa (1808-1900) - 7 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Andover., 1851-1860 (Box 21, Folder 405)
    - Parker, Peter - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1841 October 6 (Box 21, Folder 406)
    - Perkins, B. - Printed circular, American Quarterly Observer, with manuscript note to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1833 March 26 (Box 21, Folder 407)
    - Perkins, Henry - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Philadelphia., 1835 December 15 (Box 21, Folder 408)
    - Philbrick, John D. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Boston., 1859 June 21 (Box 21, Folder 409)
    - Pickering, John - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Boston., 1841 March 25 (Box 21, Folder 410)
    - Pickering, Mary - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Salem., 1857 April 14 (Box 21, Folder 411)
    - Porcher, Frederick A. (1809-1888) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Charleston., 1852 January 27 (Box 21, Folder 412)
    - Porter, Noah (1781-1866) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Farmington., 1838 April 4, 1842 April 12 (Box 21, Folder 413)
    - Porter, Samuel (1810-1901) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Hartford., 1841 February 15 (Box 21, Folder 414)
    - Pratt, Andrew Tully (1826-1872) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Anitab., 1855 August 1 (Box 21, Folder 415)
    - Ripley, George (1802-1880) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1860 May 16 and June 6 and October 30 (Box 21, Folder 416)
    - Rockwell, Elijah Frink (1809-1888) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Davidson College, North Carolina., 1858 May 13, 1859 March 23 (Box 21, Folder 417)
    - Rubinson, T. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Philadelphia., 1851 November 1 (Box 21, Folder 418)
    - St. John, Samuel - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Canaan., 1837 February 18 (Box 21, Folder 419)
    - Salem, Massachusetts Exchange Bank - Printed note to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Salem., 1830 February 2 (Box 21, Folder 420)
    - Salisbury, Edward Elbridge (1814-1901) - 3 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Oxford, New Haven., 1836 July 9, 1842 November 8, 1848 June 29 (Box 21, Folder 421)
    - Sawyer, George - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Exeter, New Hampshire; Utica., 1858 March 15, 1859 January 16 (Box 21, Folder 422)
    - Silliman, Benjamin - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1843 August 21, 1858 November 15 (Box 21, Folder 423)
      The 1843 letter includes a note from Day to Gibbs.
    - Smalley, George W. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Worcester., 1851 September 16 (Box 21, Folder 424)
    - Smith, Francis O. J. - Printed telegraph alphabet to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Boston., 1846 August 1 (Box 21, Folder 425)
    - Smythe, C. W. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Newton, North Carolina., 1858 December 9 (Box 21, Folder 426)
    - Sophocles, Evangelinus Apostolides (1807-1883) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Cambridge., 1857 July 16 (Box 21, Folder 427)
    - Sprague, Wiliam Buell (1795-1876) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Albany., 1849 March 2 and December 4 (Box 21, Folder 428)
    - Sprigg, Samuel - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Northampton., 1831 January 26, 1832 January 19 (Box 21, Folder 429)
    - Stoever, M. L. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Pennsylvania College., 1848 August 18 (Box 21, Folder 430)
    - Stone, A. L. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1843 August 17 (Box 21, Folder 431)
    - Stone, James A. B. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Gloucester., 1841 May 13 (Box 21, Folder 432)
      Includes a printed prospectus of Hexaglott New Testament.
    - Stuart, Moses - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1829 May 23 (Box 21, Folder 433)
    - Tappan, Lewis (1788-1873) - 5 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1841 July 23-December 1 (Box 21, Folder 434)
    - Tarbox, Increase - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Boston., 1851 July 10 (Box 21, Folder 435)
    - Thatcher, Thomas A. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1853 July 2 (Box 21, Folder 436)
    - Thompson, A. C. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Roxbury., 1860 April 10 (Box 21, Folder 437)
    - Thompson, Joseph P. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1857 July 3 (Box 21, Folder 438)
    - Tooley, Henry - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Natchez and New Haven., 1846 August 27 and September 16 (Box 21, Folder 439)
    - Turner, Samuel H. (1790-1861) - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1831 January 22, 1852 December 21 (Box 21, Folder 440)
    - Turner, William W. (1810-1859) - 5 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York and Washington, D.C., 1843-1853 (Box 21, Folder 441)
    - Waite, A. M. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New Haven., 1851 July 11 (Box 21, Folder 442)
    - Waterman, C. - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1851 April 27 (Box 21, Folder 443)
    - Wheatland, Henry (1812-1893) - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Salem., 1858 May 4 (Box 21, Folder 444)
    - White, Henry - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). New York., 1843 May 19 (Box 21, Folder 445)
    - Wilson, Jacob - 2 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Canajohanie., 1860 November 12 and 26 (Box 21, Folder 446)
    - Withington, William - Autograph letter, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Dorchester, Massachusetts., 1835 June 14 (Box 21, Folder 447)
    - Worcester, Joseph Emerson (1784-1865) - 10 autograph letters, signed, to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861). Cambridge., 1846-1860 (Box 21, Folder 448)
    - Miscellaneous materials and notes relating to Josiah Willard Gibbs (1790-1861)., 1813-1855 (Box 21, Folder 449)